{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Who co-founded Apple Inc. alongside Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak?",
      "options": ["Tim Cook", "Bill Gates", "Ronald Wayne", "Steve Ballmer"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which technology is often associated with the concept of “smart cities”?",
      "options": ["Augmented Reality", "Internet of Things", "Edge Computing", "Autonomous Vehicles"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the acronym API stand for in programming?",
      "options": ["Application Programming Interface", "Advanced Programming interface", "Automated Program Interface", "Algorithmic Protocol Interface"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the first high-level programming language developed?",
      "options": ["COBOL", "Fortran", "Assembly Language", "BASIC"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which virtual reality headset is developed by Oculus, a subsidiary of Facebook?",
      "options": [
        "HTC Hive",
        "Playstation VR",
        "Octulus Rift",
        "Microsoft HoloLens"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which component of a computer is often referred to as the ‘brain’ and performs most of the processing tasks?",
      "options": ["RAM", "Hard Drive", "Microprocessor", "CPU"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mobile operating system is developed by Google and based on Linux Kernel ?",
      "options": [
        "IOS",
        "Android",
        "Windows Phone",
        "Blackberry OS"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is considered the father of World Wide Web?",
      "options": [
        "Tim Cook",
        "Tim Berners-Lee",
        "Steve Jobs",
        "Mark Zuckerberg"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What design pattern is used to provide a simple interfaceto a set of interfaces in a subsystem, making subsystem easier to use",
      "options": [
        "Singleton",
        "Observer",
        "Facade",
        "Decorator"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which company developed the first graphical user interface(GUI) for personal computers?",
      "options": [
        "IBM",
        "Microsoft",
        "Apple",
        "Google"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which version control system is widely used in software development for tracking changes in source code?",
      "options": [
        "GIT",
        "Mercurial",
        "SVN",
        "CVS"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a 'firewall' in the context of computer security ?",
      "options": [
        "Virus Protecton",
        "Network Monitoring",
        "Unauthorized access prevention",
        "Data encryption"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which organization played a role in the development of the internet’s predecessor, ARPANET ?",
      "options": ["IBM", "DARPA", "Xerox", "Bell Labs"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Microsoft AI technology, released in 2020, became known for generating human-like text?",
      "options": [
        "Cortana",
        "Azure AI",
        "Power BI",
        "GPT-3"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which markup language is used for structuring conntent on the web and stands for Hyper Text Markup?",
      "options": [
        "XML",
        "HTML",
        "CSS",
        "Javascript"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}
